本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译创作
欢迎爱好者加入我们  www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译： 3ccchange  （Sammy）  丁丁猫哒   haloukeiti
校对：海因里希 监制：可乐嘻嘻  后期：LP
■
你们是华盛顿来的吗？
You're the guys from Washington?
这地方还有别人来吗？
You get many other visitors out here?
你到这儿多久了？
How long you been on site?
早上就到了
Since this morning.
18小时前  一个俄罗斯石油小队发现的
A Russian oil team called it in about 18 hours ago.
之前怎么没发现？
How come nobody's spotted it before?
没什么好奇怪的
It's really not that surprising.
这里的地貌一直在变
This landscapes changing all the time.
你知道这到底是什么玩意吗？
You got any idea what this thing is exactly?
不知道  可能是个气象气球
I don't know, it's probably a weather balloon.
我觉得不是
I don't think so.
我们没有专用的设备
You know we don't have the equipment for a job like this.
什么时候才能开始挖？
How long before we can start craning it out?
我觉得你还没搞清楚
I don't think you quite understand.
你们得要一架终极起重机才行
You guys are going to need one hell of a crane.
总部  我们进去了
Base, we're in.
这是什么？
What is this?
小心点
Careful.
中尉
Lieutenant.
- 这是什么？  - 天啊
- What is it? - My god.
总部  帮我接上校
Base, give me a line to the Colonel.
现在是凌晨三点  长官
It's 3am, sir.
我才不管现在几点
I don't care what time it is.
他已经等得够久了
This one's waited long enough.
1942年3月  挪威  滕斯贝格市
他们来了
They've come for it.
以前也来过
They have before.
这次不一样
Not like this.
让他们来吧
Let them come.
他们找不到的
They'll never find it.
快打开
Open it.
你们怎么就找不到？
Why can't you find it?
我花了很久才找到这里
It has taken me a long time to find this place.
真是不得不称赞你
You should be commended.
扶他起来
Help him up.
我想你是个很有远见的人
I think that you are a man of great vision.
这点我们很像
And in this way we are much alike.
我们根本不像
I am nothing like you.
是吗  但其他人看做是迷信的东西
Of course but what others see as superstition,
你我却都认为是科学
you and I know to be as science.
你要找的东西并不存在
What you seek is just a legend.
那又何必这么大费周章地藏起来？
Then why make such an effort to conceal it?
超立方体是奥丁的瑰宝
The tesseract was the jewel of Odin's treasure room.
这东西不该被藏起来
It's not something one buries.
但我觉得已经很接近了
But I think it is close, yes.
我帮不了你
I cannot help you.
是啊
No.
但也许你能帮帮你的村子？
But maybe you can help your, uh village?
那里一定有你的朋友
You must have some friends out there.
可能还有一些小孩子
Some little grandchildren, perhaps.
我想你不希望他们死
You have no need for them to die.
伊戈德拉希尔
Yggdrasil.
北欧神话中的一棵巨树  树根分别深扎在地狱  巨人大陆和仙宫三处
世界之树
The Tree of the world.
守护着智慧
Guardian of wisdom.
还有命运
And fate also.
元首竟还在沙漠里挖破烂
And the Fürer digs for trinkets in the desert.
你肯定没见过这个
You have never seen this.
是吧？
Have you?
这不是给凡人看的
It's not for the eyes of ordinary men.
没错
Exactly.
下令开火
Give the order to open fire.
蠢货
Fool.
你驾驭不了那种力量
You cannot control the power you hold.
你会下地狱
You will burn.
我已经见过地狱了
I already have.
迈克尔・奥康纳
O'Connell, Michael.
亨利・卡明斯基
Kaminski, Henry.
天哪  死了这么多人
Boy, a lot of guys getting killed over there.
史蒂文・罗杰斯
Rogers, Stephen.
这下你是不是有点退缩了？
Kinda makes you think twice about enlisting, huh?
没有
Nope.
罗杰斯
Rogers.
你父亲因什么过世？
What did your father die of?
芥子气
Mustard gas.
一种一战时流行的生化武器
他曾服役于107步兵团
He was in the 107th infantry.
- 我也希望能被指派到…  - 你母亲呢？
- I was hoping I could be assigned... - Mother?
她是结核病房的护士
She was a nurse in a TB ward.
她被传染了
Got hit.
没挺过去
Couldn't shake it.
病例汇总: 猩红热  风湿热  慢性或急性伤寒  高血压  心悸  乏力  心脏病等
对不起  孩子
Sorry son.
给我个机会吧
Well just give me a chance.
光哮喘这一项就不行
You'll be ineligible on your asthma alone.
你就不能做些什么吗？
Is there anything you can do?
我在做
I'm doing it.
我在救你
I'm saving your life.
不合格
战火继续肆虐欧洲
War continues to ravage Europe.
但援兵已经准备就绪
But help is on the way.
所有适龄青年都应参军报效国家
Every able bodied young man is lining up to serve his country.
就连小蒂米也出力了
Even little Timmy is doing his part.
帮忙收集废金属
Collecting scrap metal.
干得好  蒂米
Nice work, Timmy.
谁关心这个！
Who cares!
赶紧放电影
Play the movie already.
放尊重点
Hey, want to show some respect.
与此同时  海外战场上
Meanwhile, over seas...
勇敢的士兵们正让轴心国明白
..Our brave boys are showing the Axis Powers...
为了自由他们能付出一切
..That the price of freedom is never to high.
得了  别放了
Let's go, get on with it.
快放动画片
Hey, just start the cartoon.
你给我闭嘴
Hey, you want to shut up.
只要盟军齐心协力
Together with allied forces,
就能克服一切困难
we'll face any threat, no matter the size.
你就是怎么也不放弃是吧
You just don't know when to give up, do you.
我可以和你耗一整天
I can do this all day.
喂  别恃强凌弱
Hey, pick on someone your own size.
有时候我觉得你就是喜欢挨揍
Sometimes I think you like getting punched.
我就要打败他了
I had him on the ropes.
你要来多少次？
How many times is this?
这次是帕拉姆斯人啊
Oh, your from Paramus now.
你知道在征兵表上造假是违法的吗
You know it's illegal to lie on your enlistment form.
居然还有新泽西  真的假的？
Seriously, Jersey?
你接到命令了吗？
You get your orders?
107步兵团
107th.
詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士
Sergeant James Barnes.
明早起航开赴英格兰
Shipping out for England first thing tomorrow.
我也该一起去
I should be going.
来吧  哥们
Come on, man.
我参军前的最后一晚
My last night.
先帮你换身行头
Gotta get you cleaned off.
怎么  我们要去哪？
Why, where we going?
未来
The future.
明日世界世博会
我没觉得有什么问题
I don't see what the problem is.
纽约所有的男人都去当兵了
You're about to be the last eligible man in New York.
还剩下三百五十万女人
You know there's three and a half million women here.
而我只需要一个
Yeah, I'd settle for just one.
好在我已经搞定了
Good thing I took care of that.
鹿仔！
Hey, Bucky!
你怎么和她说我的？
What'd you tell her about me?
都是好话
Only the good stuff.
欢迎来到现代奇迹展馆
Welcome to the Modern Marvels Pavilion.
明日世界
and the world of tomorrow.
更强大的世界
A greater world.
更完美的世界
A better world.
我的天啊
Oh my god.
开始了
It's starting.
女士们先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen,
有请霍华德・史塔克先生
Mr. Howard Stark.
女士们先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen.
要是我告诉你就在短短几年后
What if I told you that in just a few short years,
你的汽车就再也不用碰到地面
Your automobile won't even have to touch the ground, at all.
是的
Yes.
谢谢  曼蒂
Thanks, Mandy.
只要有史塔克的反重力科技
With Starks Gravitic reversion technology.
这一切都将成为可能
You'll be able to do just that.
我的神啊
Holy cow.
我说了还要再过几年是吧？
Well I did say a few years, didn't I?
史蒂夫  我们请这些女孩去…
Hey, Steve. What do you say we treat these girls...
来吧  大兵
Come on, Soldier.
来吧  不然还叫什么双人约会
Come on, kinda missing the point of a double date.
我们去跳舞
We're taking the girls dancing.
你去吧  我一会来找你们
You go ahead, I'll catch up with you.
你真要再试一次吗？
You really gonna do this again?
反正这是嘉年华  就当我碰碰运气
Well it's a fair, I'm going to try my luck.
这次又是哪  俄亥俄州吗？
As who, Steve from Ohio?
他们会逮住你  要是他们招了你就更糟
They'll catch you or worse they'll actually take you.
我知道你觉得我不行
Look I know you don't think I can do this.
这可不是打架  史蒂夫  这是打仗
This isn't a back alley, Steve, it's war.
- 我知道这是打仗  - 那就去找点事做
- I know it's a war. - Then find something to fight,
先去找份工作
..Start looking for a job.
那你觉得我能干什么  捡垃圾吗
What am I going to do, collect scrap.
对  我知道…
Yes, I know that I'm...
我不想去工厂  鹿仔
I'm not going to sit in a factory, Bucky.
鹿仔  拜托了
Bucky come on,
大家都在战场上拼命
there are men laying down their lives.
我不能躲在后方
I got no right to do any less than them.
你不会了解这点
That's what you don't understand.
我不是想证明什么
This isn't about me.
才怪
Right.
你就是想证明自己
'Cause you got nothing to prove.
不好意思  我们还去跳舞吗？
Hey sorry. Are we going dancing?
当然了
Yes we are.
别干傻事  等我回来
Don't do anything stupid until I get back.
我怎么会？
How can I?
你把傻气都带走了
You're taking all the stupid with you.
你个混球
You're a punk.
你才混球
Jerk.
小心点
Careful.
等我到了再打赢战争
Don't win the war 'til I get there.
来吧  姑娘们  我们去跳舞
Come on girls, playing our song.
在这等着
Wait here.
怎么了吗？
Is there a problem?
在这等着就是
Just wait here.
伪造征兵资料是违法的
谢谢
Thank you.
这么说
So.
你想到国外
You want to go overseas.
去杀鬼子吗
Kill some Nazis.
你说什么
Excuse me.
我是亚伯罕・厄斯金博士
Doctor Abraham Erskine.
战略科学预备役部门
I represent a Strategic Scientific Reserve.
史蒂夫・罗杰斯
Steve Rogers.
你是哪里人？
Where are you from?
皇后区
Queens.
乌托邦大道第73街
73rd street and Utopla parkway.
在那之前  是德国人
Before that, Germany.
这会让你困扰吗？
This troubles you?
不
No.
你又是哪里人  罗杰斯先生？
Where are you from, Mr. Rogers? Hmm?
是纽黑文市？
Is it, New Haven?
还是帕拉姆斯？
Or, Paramus?
五份文件上写了五个不同城市…
Five exams in five different cities...
文件可能拿错了
It might not be the right file.
我感兴趣的不是文件
It's not the exams I'm interested in.
而是你尝试了五次
It's the five tries.
但你还没回答我的问题
But you didn't answer my question.
你想去杀鬼子吗？
Do you want to kill Nazis?
这是测试吗？
Is this a test?
是的
Yes.
我不想杀任何人
I don't want to kill anyone.
我不想当恶霸
I don't like bullies.
不管是哪里的人
I don't care where they're from.
已经有很多大个子参战了
Well, there are already so many big men fighting this war.
现在不妨加一个小个子
Maybe what we need now is a little guy.
我可以给你一个机会
I can offer you a chance.
只是一个机会
Only a chance.
我接受
I'll take it.
很好
Good.
那么这个小个子从哪来？
So where is the little guy from?
说实话
Actually.
布鲁克林
Brooklyn.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
大兵
Soldier.
一等
准备好了吗  佐拉博士？
Are you ready, Doctor Zola?
这台仪器需要精确无比的校准
The machine requires the most delicate calibration.
请原谅  我不得不确保万无一失
Forgive me if I seem over cautious.
你确定那些士兵
Are you certain that those combatants of yours
能承受这种能量激增
...can withstand the energy surge,
能接受这种变形吗？
strong enough for a transference?
在这个装置面前
With this artifact.
我什么都不能确定
I am certain of nothing.
我担心它完全不起作用
I fear it may not work at all.
百分之二十
Twenty percent.
四十
Forty.
六十
Sixty.
稳定在百分之七十
Stabilizing at seventy percent.
我花了这么多功夫
I have not come all this way,
可不是为了安全  博士
...for safety, Doctor.
那是什么？
What was that?
我要恭喜你  阿尔宁
I must congratulate you, Arnim.
你的设计没有让我失望
Your designs does not disappoint.
虽然还需要一点加固
Though they may require some slight reinforcement.
转换过程很稳定
The transmittion is stable.
太神奇了
Amazing.
你说的那个能量源
The energy patch, you called it,
使我所有的设计
equipped all my designs.
变成了现实
All my designs.
这将改变这场战争
This will change the war.
佐拉博士
Doctor Zola.
这将改变整个世界
This will change the world.
新兵们  立正！
Recruits, attention!
先生们  我是卡特特工
Gentlemen, I'm Agent Carter.
我负责监督该部门的所有事务
I supervise all operations for this division.
你的口音怎么了  维多利亚女王？
What's with the accent, Queen Victoria?
我还以为我是为美军效力
Thought I was signing up for the U.S. Army.
你叫什么名字  大兵？
What's your name, soldier?
吉尔默・霍奇  女王陛下
Gilmore Hodge, your majesty.
上前一步  霍奇
Step forward, Hodge.
右脚再上前一步
Put your right foot forward.
我们要格斗吗？
We gonna wrestle?
我可有个你会喜欢的招式哟
'Cause I gotta a few moves I know you'll like.
卡特特工
Agent Carter.
菲利普斯上校
Colonel Phillips.
看来你和我们的新兵打成一片啊
I can see that you are breaking in the candidates,
不错嘛
that's good.
把你的屁股从地上挪开
Get your ass up out of that dirt,
然后归队站好
..And stand up in that lineup at attention until,
站到有人让你停为止
...somebody comes and tells you what to do.
是  长官
Yes, Sir.
巴顿将军
General Patton.
曾经说过
Has said.
"战争取决于武器  但战胜取决于士兵"
"War's are fought with weapons but they are won by men."
我们会打赢这场仗  因为
We are going to win this war, because...
我们有最优秀的士兵
...we have the best men.
而且他们会越来越好
And because they're gonna get better.
好得多
Much, better.
战略科学预备队
The Strategic Scientific Reserve.
是又各国同盟组成
Is an allied effort.
由自由世界的精英们组成
Made up with the best minds of the free world.
我们的目标
Our goal.
是建立史上最优秀的军队
Is to create the best army in history.
而所有军队都有一个先行者
But every army starts with one man.
罗杰斯！  快起来
Rogers! Get up from there.
这周过后  我们就要选出那个人
At the end of this week, we will chose that man.
他将会是第一个
He'll be the first.
我们新一代的超级战士
Our new breed of super soldiers.
罗杰斯  快从那爬出来
Rogers, get your ass out of that line.
而他们  将亲手把阿道夫・希特勒
And they, will personally escort Adolph Hitler
送进地狱
Through the gates of hell.
跟上  姑娘们
Pick up the pace, ladies.
快跑
Let's go, let's go.
跑起来
Double time.
快点  跑快点
Come on, faster, faster.
动起来
Move.
立定
Squad halt.
这面旗子说明你们只跑了一半
That flag means you're only at the half way point.
第一个拿到旗子的人
First man to bring it to me,
就能和卡特特工一起搭车
gets to ride back with Agent Carter.
快去！
Move, move!
快点  爬上去
Come on, get up there.
你们就这点能耐吗？  这支部队完了
That's what you got? This army is in trouble.
上去啊  霍奇
Get up there, Hodge.
上啊  爬上去
Come on, get up there.
17年来没人能拿到那面旗子
Nobody's got that flag in seventeen years.
快点  排队
Come on, come on, fall in.
快点  回来排好队
Let's go, get back in a formation.
罗杰斯！
Rogers!
我说排队
I said, fall in.
谢了  长官
Thank you, Sir.
快点  姑娘们
Faster ladies, come on.
连我奶奶都比你们强力
My grandmother has more life in her,
上帝保佑她  动起来！
God rest her soul. Move it!
你不是真想选罗杰斯吧？
You're not really thinking of picking Rogers, are you?
不是想  我已经决定选他了
I am more than just thinking about it.
这是个明智的选择
It is a clear choice.
你当时把个90磅的哮喘病猫
When you brought a 90 pounds
带进我部队的时候
modicum asthmatic onto my army base.
我没反对  我想管他呢
I let it slide. I thought what the hell.
也许你只把他当做小白鼠
Maybe he could be useful to you, like a gerbil.
- 我从没想过你会选他  - 起来
- Never thought you'd pick him. - Up.
这孩子的胳膊
Stick a needle in that kids arm,
比面条都细
it's going to go right through him.
快点  姑娘们
Come on, girls.
看看他
Look at that.
我看着他都快哭了
He's making me cry.
我更看重品质  而不是体型
I am looking for qualities beyond the physical.
你知道我们为这项目付出多少心血
Do you know how long it took to set up this project.
- 我知道  - 我还不得不对那些
- Yes. - All the groveling I had to do in front...
天知道叫什么名字的狗屁委员会低声下气
...of Senator whats-his-name committees.
是的  我清楚你付出了多少努力
Yes, I know. I am well aware of your efforts.
那就给我点回报
Then throw me a bone.
霍奇通过了所有测试
Hodge passed every test we gave him.
他强壮  动作又快
He's big, he's fast.
他遵守命令  是个军人
He obeys orders, he's a soldier.
他是个恶霸
He's a bully.
靠善良可打不了胜仗  博士
You don't win wars with niceness, Doctor.
打胜仗  靠的是胆量
You win wars, with guts.
有手榴弹！
Grenade!
快跑
Stay away.
躲起来
Get back.
是假手榴弹
Phony grenade.
警报解除  归队
All clear, back in formation.
这是测试吗？
Is this a test?
他还是太瘦弱了
He's still skinny.
- 我能进来吗？  - 当然
- May I? - Yeah.
睡不着吗？
Can't sleep?
可能是紧张吧
Got the jitters I guess.
我也是
Oh, me too.
我能问个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
就一个吗？
Just one?
为什么选我？
Why me?
只要这一个问题就够了
I suppose that is the one question that matters.
这个产自奥格斯堡[德国城市]
This is from Augsburg.
我的故乡
My City.
很多人都忘了
So many people forget that the
纳粹第一个侵略的就是自己的国家
first country the Nazi's invaded was their own.
一战结束后
You know after the last war they,
我的同胞们生活在水深火热中
my peoples struggled, they..They..
他们感到无能为力
They felt weak, they felt..
然后希特勒出现了
...slow, then Hitler comes along.
军队  党旗  大肆宣扬  各种煽动
With the marching and the big show, and the flags and all that
接着他听说了我
And he, hears of me.
还有我的工作  他找到了我
My work, and he finds me.
他说  你
Then he says, you.
你要让我们变强
He says, you will make us strong.
而我不感兴趣
I am not interested.
他把我送到海德拉总部
So he sends the head of Hydra.
希腊神话中的九头蛇  被砍去一头会长出两个头  后被大力神赫拉克勒斯杀死
东线研究部门
East research division.
有位天才科学家  叫约翰・施密特
A brilliant Scientist by the name of, Johann Schmidt.
现在施密特已经是核心成员了
Now Schmidt is a member of the inner circle.
他野心勃勃
And he's ambitious.
他甚至和希特勒一样
Even Hitler shares his passion for,
痴迷于超能力和大陆神话
occult power and tatanic myth.
希特勒用他的幻想煽动他的追随者
Hitler uses his fantasies to inspire his followers.
而对施密特来说那不是幻想
But for Schmidt it is not fantasy.
对他来说  这是真的
For him, it is real.
他相信在这个世界上
He has become convinced that there is a great power.
隐藏着一股强大的力量
Hidden in the earth.
是众神留下的
Left here by the gods.
有待一个超人去发现
Waiting to be seized by superior men.
所以当他发现我血清配方的能耐
So when he has found my formula and what it can do.
他无法抗拒
He cannot resist.
施密特想成为那个超人
Schmidt wants to become that superior man.
他变强了吗？
Did it make him stronger?
是的
Ja.
不过也有副作用
But, it has other effects.
那血清还未完全成熟
The serum wasn't ready.
但更重要的是
But more important.
是使用的人
The man.
血清能增强人的各个方面  所以
The serum amplifies everything that is inside, so..
好的变得更好
Good becomes great.
坏的则变得更坏
Bad becomes worse.
所以我选择了你
This is why you were chosen.
因为强者的力量与生俱来
Because a strong man who has known power all his life.
他们失去了对力量的敬畏
They lose respect for that power.
而弱者
But a weak man.
才懂得力量的价值
Who values of strength.
有爱心
And loves
懂得怜悯
Compassion.
谢谢  虽然不太懂
Thanks. I think.
来喝点
Give this.
不管明天发生什么  答应我一件事
Whatever happens tomorrow, you must promise me one thing.
永远别忘了你是谁
That you must stay who you are.
不要当一个好兵
Not a perfect soldier.
而要当
But.
一个好人
A good man.
敬小个子们
To the little guys.
慢着  看我做了什么？
No, wait, wait. What am I doing?
你明天要进行测试
No, you have procedure tomorrow.
不能喝酒
No fluids.
好吧  那我们以后再喝
All right, we'll drink it after.
不  我明天又不用测试
No, I don't have procedure tomorrow.
我不用等  我现在就喝
I can't after, I can now.
你有什么特别需要吗？
Is there something in particular you need?
我听说你找到他了
I uh, understand you found him.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
你不赞成吗
You disapprove.
我只是不明白你为什么要在意他
I just don't see why you need concern yourself.
他不可能成功
I can't imagine he'll succeed.
再次成功
Again.
血清是同盟国最后的防线
The serum is the allies only defense.
来抵抗我们掌握了的力量
against this power we now possess.
若是我们将其摧毁  就能确保胜利
If we take it away from them, then our victory is assured.
那我要下令吗？
Shall I give the order?
我已经下令了
It has been given.
很好
Good.
佐拉博士
Doctor Zola.
你觉得怎样？
What do you think?
杰作
Masterpiece.
这个街区我很熟悉
I know this neighborhood.
我在那条巷子里被打过
I got beat up in that alley.
还有那个停车场
And that parking lot.
还有那个餐厅后面
And behind that dinner.
你为什么不逃跑？
Did you have something against running away?
你要是跑了一次  就会一直跑下去
You start running they'll never let you stop.
而你要是站起来反击
You stand up, push back.
总有一天会有机会的吧
You can't say no forever, right.
我和你有一点同感
I know a little of what that's like.
总是被拒绝的感觉
To have every door shut in your face.
我不明白你为什么要参军
I guess I just don't know why you would want to join the army.
你是位漂亮的女士  我是说漂亮的女人
You're a beautiful dame. Beautifu..Oh a woman. I mean...
是位特工  不是女士
An agent, not a Dame.
你很漂亮
You are beautiful.
你不知道怎么跟女人搭讪吧？
You have no idea how to talk to a woman, do you?
这大概是我和女人的最长一次对话了
I think this is the longest conversation I've had with a woman.
她们才不愿意和一个
They're not exactly lining
会踩到她们脚的男人跳舞
up to dance with a guy that might step on them.
你肯定跳过舞吧
You must have danced.
我不敢邀女人跳舞
Well, asking a woman to dance always seems so terrifying.
而这么些年过去
And the past few years just...
我已经不怎么在意了
Didn't seem to matter that much.
我想我在等吧
Figured I'd wait.
等什么？
For what?
合适的舞伴
Right partner.
这边走
This way.
我们来这儿干什么？
What are we doing here?
跟我来
Follow me.
布鲁克林古董店
今天天气很棒吧
Wonderful weather this morning. Isn't it.
是啊  但我总是带着伞
Yes, but I always carry an umbrella.
早上好
Good morning.
拜托  别拍
Please, not now.
准备好了吗？
You ready?
很好
Good.
脱掉衬衣和领带  摘掉帽子
Take off your shirt your tie and your hat.
布兰德议员  很高兴你能来
Senator Brandt, glad you could make it.
我到底来这儿干什么来了？
Why exactly am I in Brooklyn?
我们需要使用城市电网
We needed access to the cities power grid.
当然如果你之前批准了我的申请
Of course if you had given me a generalized requisition.
很多人都在申请经费
A lot of people are asking for funds, ....
这位是克雷…
Oh, this is Clem uh...
格雷格・克雷姆森  国务院的
Gregg Clemson, state department.
如果你们的项目获得成功
If this project of yours comes through.
我们可不能让媒体抢了先机啊
We'd like to see that it doesn't get into the headlines.
老天爷
Jesus.
给那孩子吃点东西吧
Somebody get that kid a sandwich.
舒服吗？
Comfortable?
有点大
It's a little big.
那酒有没有给我留？
You save me any of that schnapps?
没留多少
Not as much as I should have.
不好意思  下次吧
Sorry, next time.
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
基线如何？
How are your levels?
- 100%  - 很好
- Levels at 100%. - Good.
我们可能会用掉布鲁克林一半电力
We may dim half the lights in Brooklyn.
但我们准备好了
But we are ready.
一如既往
Good as we'll ever be.
卡特特工  要是你待在
Agent Carter, don't you think
控制室里会不会更好点？
you would be more comfortable in the booth?
好的  抱歉
Oh yes, ah, sorry.
能听到吗？
Can you hear me, is this on?
女士们  先生们
Ladies and Gentlemen.
今天我们不是进一步走向灭绝
Today we take not another step towards annihilation.
而是迈上和平之路的第一步
But the first step towards the path to peace.
首先是一系列微创注射
We begin with a series of micro injections,
将血清注入肌肉群
into the subjects major muscles.
血清注入后会引发细胞的急速改变
The serum infusion will cause immediate cellular change.
之后会刺激生长
Then to stimulate growth.
接着会通过生命射线
The subject will be saturated,
渗透主体
...with Vita rays
感觉还行
That wasn't so bad.
这只是青霉素
That was penicillin.
注射血清
Serum infusion.
倒计时五秒
Beginning in, five...
四
Four...
三
Three...
二
Two...
一
One.
开始吧  史塔克先生
Now, Mr. Stark.
史蒂文
Steven.
能听到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
现在想去厕所是不是有点晚了？
Probably too late to go to the bathroom, right?
继续
We will proceed.
百分之十
That's ten percent.
百分之二十
Twenty percent.
三十
Thirty.
百分之四十
That's forty percent.
各项指标正常
All signs are normal.
百分之五十
That's fifty percent.
六十
Sixty.
七十
Seventy.
史蒂文
Steven, Steven.
- 快关掉！  - 史蒂文
- Shut it down! - Steven.
快关掉
Shut it down.
往回转  史塔克先生  关掉  往回转
Turn back, Mr. Stark. Turn it off kill it, turn back.
不！
No!
别关
Don't
我扛得住
I can do this.
八十  九十
Eighty...Ninety.
百分之百了！
That's one hundred percent!
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
这小子还真成功了
Son of a bitch did it.
- 我做到了  - 是的
- I did it, - Yes, yes.
我们成功了
I think we did it.
你真的成功了
You actually did it.
感觉怎样？
How do you feel?
长高了
Taller.
看起来是高了
You look taller.
下去看看吧  议员先生？
How do we look now, Senator?
这下柏林那帮家伙该紧张了
I guess the folks in Berlin are about to get very nervous.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
拦住他！
Stop him!
- 他们来了  快走  - 快
- They're coming, come on. - Now.
你没事吧？
You all right?
他中枪了
This guy's been shot.
我瞄准他了
I had him.
抱歉
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
不  不  宝贝儿  不要
No. No, darling no.
- 妈妈  - 不要  别伤害他
- Mommy. - No. Don't hurt him.
走开
Go on.
放开我
Let me go.
别伤害他
No, don't hurt him.
等等  不要
Wait don't.
不要
Don't.
住手
No, don't.
去抓他  我会游泳
Go get him, I can swim.
你到底是谁？
Who the hell are you?
先行军而已
The first of many.
砍掉一个头
Got off one head.
还会长出两个新的
Two more shall take its place.
海德拉万岁
Heil Hydra.
元首可不喜欢被无视  施密特先生
The Fürer is not accustomed to being ignored, Herr Schmidt.
你承诺为他提供武器  他才资助你的研究
He funds your research because you promised him weapons.
你得听从他的命令
You serve at his pleasure.
因为你负伤  他才将这个研究所给你作为奖励
He gave you this facility as a reward for your injuries.
奖励  这算什么奖励  这是流放
Reward, call it what it is, exile.
我不再符合他心目中雅利安人的完美形象
I no longer effect his image of Aryan perfection.
你觉得这只是外表的问题吗？
You think this is about appearances?
你的海德拉部门让人失望
Your Hydra division has failed,
一年来提供的武器比步枪强不了多少
...to deliver so much as a rifle in over a year.
而且我们从当地情报部门获知
And we have learned through local intelligence.
你们还在策划全面入侵挪威
You have mounted a full scaled incursion into Norway.
元首他担心  他怎么说的来着？
The Fürer fears, how does he put it?
不能再继续放纵红骷髅了
The Red Skull has been indulged long enough.
先生们
Gentlemen.
你们来看看我们的研究成果吧？
You have come to see the results of our work, hmm?
我给你们展示一下
Let me show you.
希特勒口口声声说德意志千秋万代
Hitler speaks of a thousand year Reich.
事实上却拿不出军队一个月的给养
But he cannot feed his armies for a month is truth.
他的部队在欧洲战场上流血牺牲
His troops spill their blood across every field in Europe.
可他的目标却还是遥遥无期
But still he is no closer to achieving his goals.
这么说你想用魔法来打赢战争
And I suppose you still aim to win this war through magic.
是科学  但我理解你的困惑
Science, but I understand your confusion.
强大的力量总是令愚昧之人感到迷惑
Great power has always baffled primitive men.
海德拉正在组建一支军队
Hydra is assembling an arsenal
能将我的敌人一网打尽
that will destroy my enemies in one stroke.
不管他们是谁  拥有多少兵力
Wherever they are, regardless of how many forces they possess.
只需几个小时就能搞定
All in a matter of hours.
你的敌人吗？
Your enemies?
我的武器具有足够破坏力
My weapons contain enough destructive power,
能摧毁世界上所有敌国的首都
...to decimate every hostile capital on Earth.
轻而易举  先生们
Quite simply, gentlemen.
我已从诸神那里获得神力
I have harnessed the power of the gods.
谢谢  施密特
Thank you, Schmidt.
谢什么？
For what?
让我们明白你有多疯狂
For making it clear how obviously mad you are.
柏林也在地图上！
Berlin is on this map!
当然了
So it is.
你要为你的傲慢付出代价
You will be punished for your insolence.
你要被带到元首面前…
You will be brought before the Fürer and ....
抱歉了  博士
My apologies, Doctor.
但我们都知道  在希特勒的阴影下  海德拉无法壮大
But we both knew Hydra could grow no further in Hitler's shadow.
海德拉万岁
Heil Hydra.
海德拉万岁！
Heil Hydra!
海德拉万岁
Heil Hydra.
可以了吗？
Think you got enough?
重新制造血清的方法
Any hope of reproducing
锁进了你的基因序列
the program is locked in your genetic code
没有厄斯金博士  这得花上好多年
But without Erskine it would take years.
他不该就这么死了
He deserved more than this.
就算只成功了这么一次
If it could work only once.
他也会以你为傲
He'd be proud of you.
菲利普斯上校  委员会需要答复
Colonel Phillips, my committee is demanding answers.
好啊  那你先说说怎么有个德国间谍
Great, why don't we start with how a German spy,
坐在你车上混进了我的秘密基地？
Got a ride to my secret installation in your car?
情况怎么样？
What do we got here?
虽然我是本国
Speaking modestly I'm the
最好的机械工程师
best mechanical engineer in this country.
但我也搞不清这东西的构造
But I don't know what's inside this thing.
还有它如何运转
Or how it works.
我们连这项技术的皮毛都没摸清
We're not even close to this technology.
那谁清楚？
Then who is?
海德拉  你应该看过我们的简报了
Hydra, I'm sure you've been reading our briefings.
我还有很多事要忙  上校
I'm on a number of committees, Colonel.
海德拉是纳粹的秘密科研部门
Hydra is a Nazi Deep science division.
由约翰・施密特领导
It's led by Johann Schmidt.
不过他有更大的野心
But he has much bigger ambitions.
海德拉其实是个邪教组织
Hydra's practically a cult,
他们把施密特奉为神  认为他无所不能
they worship Schmidt, they think he's invincible.
那你打算怎么做？
So what are you going to do about it?
今天早上我和总统通过话
I spoke to the President this morning.
从今天起  战略科学部门有了新任务
As of today, the S.S.R. is being retasked.
- 上校？  - 我们要和海德拉决一死战
- Colonel? - We are taking the fight to Hydra.
收拾行李  卡特特工
Pack your bags, Agent Carter.
你也是  史塔克
You too, Stark.
我们今晚就飞往伦敦
We're flying to London tonight.
先生
Sir.
如果你们要对付施密特  我也要加入
If you're going after Schmidt, I want in.
你是个实验品  你得去阿拉莫多[美国城市]
Your an experiment, you're going to Alamogordo.
血清起作用了
The serum worked.
我要的是一支军队  结果却只有你
I asked for an army, and all I got was you.
你一个人
You.
还远远不够
You're not enough.
不是我对上校有意见
With all due respect to the Colonel.
我觉得我们没看到重点
I think we may be missing the point.
我看到了你的能力  史蒂夫
I've seen you in action, Steve.
更重要的是
More importantly.
整个国家都看到了
The countries seen it.
拿报纸来
Paper.
自从你的事迹登报后
The enlistment lines have been
纽约参考报
纽约惊现纳粹  神秘人拯救儿童
大街上排满了想入伍的人
around the block since your picture hit the news stands.
你可不能让一个偶像级人物
You don't take a soldier, a symbol like that.
藏在实验室里
And hide him in a Lab.
孩子
Son.
你在最重要的战场
You want to serve your country.
为国家效力吗
On the most important battlefield of the war.
长官
Sir.
我求之不得
That's all I want.
那恭喜你
Then congratulations.
你升官了
You just got promoted.
我不知道我行不行
I don't know if I can do this.
这没什么大不了
Nothing to it.
推销国库券  用来买子弹
Sell a few bonds, bonds buy's bullets.
再用子弹打纳粹  砰砰砰
Bullets kill Nazi's, bing, bang, boom.
你是美国英雄
You're an American hero.
我只是觉得这我想的不一样
It's just I don't think I'm getting there.
参议员他很有势力
The senator's got a lot of pull up on the hill.
你和我们一起好好干
You play ball, with us.
很快就能领导自己的队伍了
You'll be leading your own platoon in no time.
那才是你
That's you.
上吧！
Go!
谁既强壮又勇敢  拯救美国于水火
Who's strong and brave, here to save the American way.
不是所有人都能掀起狂澜
Not all of us can storm a beach.
开动坦克
Or drive a tank.
但我们仍然可以战斗
But there's still a way all of us can fight.
谁愿意与他一样  加入我们的战斗
Who loves to fight like the man for what right by day.
E系列国防债券
Series E Defense bonds.
你每买一张战士们就会多一颗子弹
Each one you buy is a bullet in the barrel of your best guys gun.
谁为美国走遍挨家挨户？
Who built and came door to door for America?
抗着大旗插遍海岸线
Carries the flag shore to shore for America.
从霍博肯到斯波坎
From Hoboken to Spokane.
胸前顶着闪烁的星星  胸怀计划
The Star Spangled Man, with the plan.
停
Cut.
好了  别看镜头
All right, don't look at the camera.
我们不能忘记  还存在巨大威胁
We can't ignore there's a threat and the warning is big.
你每买一张战士们就会多一颗子弹
Each one you buy is a bullet in the barrel of your best guys gun.
谁会去柏林吊死纳粹
Who'll hang the noose on the goose that we loosed from Berlin.
谁会听到美国的呼唤
Who will redeem heed the call for America.
谁买谁就为美国做了贡献
Who buys it all, gives his all for America.
谁会坚持完成这个任务
Who stands to prove that task.
胸前顶着闪烁的星星  胸怀计划
The Star Spangled Man, with the plan.
这些都是为了赢得战争
We all know it's about trying to win the war.
没有子弹和绷带我们赢不了
We can't do that without bullets and bandages.
还有坦克
Tanks and casts.
该是你们出力的时候了
And that's where you come in.
你买一张国债就能保护你爱的人
Every bond you buy will help protect someone you love.
小心  他在你后面
Look out there, he's there behind you.
德国人就不敢招惹我们
The Germans will think twice about trying to get the drop on us.
坚强  坚定又真实
Stalwart, and steady and true.
看看他是怎么打败敌人的吧！
See how this guy can shoot!
我们都知道没有候补人员
We can tell that there's no substitute.
他很坚强并时刻准备好保护美国！
Forceful and ready to defend the Red, White and Blue!
谁将会打败轴心国  谁和狐狸一样聪明？
Who'll give the Axis the sack and is smart as a fox?
我们会像雄鹰一样高飞
Far as an eagle we'll soar.
谁让纳粹不敢踏出自己的地盘？
Who's making Adolph afraid to step out of his bunk?
他知道我们为何而战
He knows what we're fighting for.
我们唤醒了沉睡的巨人？
Who waked the giant that napped in America?
我们知道  他就是美国队长
We know it's no one but, Captain America.
谁将完成我们的使命？
Who'll finish what they began?
谁将把鬼子踢回日本？
Who'll kick the krauts to Japan?
星光闪烁的男人
The Star Spangled Man.
胸怀
With the...
计划
Plaaaaaaaaaan.
你们准备好和我一起去修理希特勒了吗？
How many of you are ready to help me sock ol' Adolph on the jaw?
好吧
Okay.
有志愿者吗
1943年11月  意大利
距前线五英里处
I need a volunteer.
不志愿的话我们在这干嘛？
We already volunteered, how do you think I got here?
我们要看妹子
Bring back the girls.
我想她们只唱一首歌
I think they only know the one song.
但是
But, um...
我看看我能做什么
Let me...I'll see what I can do.
去吧  甜心
You do that, sweetheart.
你的靴子不错  小仙女
Nice boots, Tinkerbell.
拜托  伙计们
Come on guys.
我们是一队的
We're all on the same team here.
队长
Hey, Captain.
在这签个名吧
Sign this.
别在意  他们会喜欢你的
Don't worry about it, they'll warm up to you. Don't worry.
你好  史蒂夫
Hello Steve.
你在这干什么？
What are you doing here?
我其实不该来这
Officially I'm not here at all.
你的表演不错
That was quite a performance.
是啊
Yeah, uh...
我得即兴表演一下
I had to improvise a little bit.
我以前的观众通常都是…
The crowds I'm used to are usually are, uh...
- 小孩  - 我知道你是美国的新希望
- twelve. - I understand you're America's new hope.
我每到一个州国债销售额就上升百分之十
Bond sales take a ten percent bump on every state I visit.
听起来是布拉德参议员的主意
That's Senator Brandt's idea.
至少他还让我做这些
At least he's got me doing this.
菲利普斯还想把我关在实验室里
Phillips would have had me stuck in a lab.
你只有这两个选择吗？
And these are you only two options?
实验室小白鼠或是跳舞的猴子
A lab rat or a dancing monkey.
要知道  你能做的远不止这些
You were meant for more than this, you know.
怎么了？
What?
我长久以来的梦想
You know, for the longest time I dreamed about,
就是去国外战场
...coming over seas and...
到最前线
..Being on the front lines.
为我的国家效力
Serving my country.
等到我终于如愿以偿
Finally got everything I wanted.
却是穿着紧身衣
And I'm wearing tights.
他们好像刚打了一场恶仗
Look like they've been through hell.
这些士兵最惨
These men move the most.
施密特派出了一支部队
Schmidt sent out a force to a zone.
两百名士兵去迎战
200 men went up against him.
回来的不到五十个
Less than 50 returned.
你的观众里就有107步兵团的人
Your audience contained what was left of the 107th.
其他人的不是被杀就是被俘
The rest were killed or captured.
107步兵团？
The 107th?
怎么了？
What?
快来
Come on.
菲利普斯上校
Colonel Phillips.
这不是胸前顶着星星藏着计划的男人嘛
Well, if it isn't the Star Spangled Man with the plan.
你今天有什么计划呀？
What is your plan today?
我要博尔扎诺战役的伤亡名单
I need the causality list from Bolzano.
你没资格命令我  小子
You don't get to give me orders, son.
我只想知道107步兵团的詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士的情况
I just need one name. Sergeant James Barnes from the 107th.
等我之后再找你算账
You and I are going to have a conversation later that you won't enjoy.
拜托你告诉我他还活着  B A R
Please tell me he's alive, sir. B-A-R...
我知道怎么拼
I can spell.
我今天签了很多哀悼信
I've signed more of these
名字我都记不清了
condolence letters today than I would care to count.
但是
But...
这个名字我有印象
The name does sound familiar.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那其他人呢？
What about the others?
你们准备去营救吗？
Are you planning a rescue mission?
必须以大局为重
Yeah, it's called winning the war.
但既然你知道他们在哪  为什么…
But if you know where they are, why not...
他们在敌阵后方三十英里
They're thirty miles behind the lines.
得穿过欧洲戒备最森严的地区
Through some of the most heavily fortified territory in Europe.
去营救只会损失更多人
We'd lose more men than we'd save.
我不指望你能理解这些
I don't expect you to understand that,
因为你只是个跳舞的小丑
because you're a chorus girl.
我想我能理解
I think I understand just fine.
那去其他地方理解吧
Well then understand it somewhere else.
如果我没看错海报的话
If I read the posters correctly,
你得在三十分钟内赶到其他地方
you've got someplace to be in thirty minutes.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我会的
I do.
如果你有什么想说
If you have something to say,
现在最好别说
right now is the perfect time to keep it to yourself.
你有什么计划  走去奥地利吗
What do plan to do, walk to Austria.
如果可以的话
If that's what it takes.
你听到上校说的了  你朋友可能已经死了
You heard the Colonel, your friend is most likely dead.
但不能确定
You don't know that.
即便如此  制定计划需要时间
Even so, he's devising a strategy, it takes time.
等他计划好了就已经晚了
By the time he's done that, it could be too late.
史蒂夫
Steve.
你说过我能做的远不止这些
You told me you thought I was meant for more than this.
是真的吗？
Did you mean that?
千真万确
Every word.
那就让我去
Then you gotta let me go.
我能做的不止这点
I can do more than that.
上台了  姑娘们
On stage, girls.
我的头盔呢？
Where's my helmet?
有人看到罗杰斯吗？
Anyone seen Rogers?
海德拉军营在克劳斯堡
The Hydra camp is in Krossberg.
在两座山脉之间
It's up between these two mountain ranges.
就像一个工厂
It's a factory of some kind.
我们会把你送到门口
We should be able to drop you around the doorstep.
尽可能地接近目标
Just get me as close as you can.
你们着陆后
You know you two are going
会有很多麻烦
to be in a lot of trouble when you land.
- 你不也是  - 我要是遇到麻烦
- And you won't. - Where I'm going if any anybody,
开枪打他们就行
...yells at me I can just shoot them.
他们也会开枪打你
And they will undoubtedly shoot back.
那就指望这玩意有用吧
Well lets hope this is good for something.
卡特特工
Agent Carter.
如果你不是那么赶时间
If you're not in too much of a hurry I thought
我想我们过会可以去享受一下芝士火锅
we could stop off in Usurea for a late night Fondue.
史塔克是我见过最好的平民飞行员
Stark is the best civilian pilot I've ever seen.
只有他敢在这种气候起飞  有他在是我们走运
He's mad enough to brave this air space. We're lucky to have him.
所以你们俩？
So you two?
你真要去？
Do you?
芝士火锅吗？
Fondue?
这是收发器  准备好就启动
This is your transponder, active it when you're ready.
我们会根据信号找到你
And the signal will lead us straight to you.
你确定这管用吗？
Are you sure this thing works?
它测试的次数比你还多  伙计
It tested more than you, pal.
回来  我们要把你送到门口
Get back here, we're taking you all the way there.
我要跳了
I'm jumping this plane,
你们赶紧掉头离开这鬼地方
turn this thing around and get the hell out of here.
你不能命令我
You can't give me orders.
我当然可以
The hell I can't.
我是队长
I'm a Captain.
正如你所见
As you can see.
瓦尔基里正按计划在建造中
Production of Valkyrie is progressing on schedule.
即使是这种大小的零件
Even with components of this size.
将进度提高百分之六十
Increase the output by sixty percent.
其他研究所也一样
And speak with our other facilities to do the same.
但这些都是囚犯  我想他们没这力气
But these prisoners, I'm not sure they have the strength.
那就用尽他们的力气  博士
Then use up what strength they have left, Doctor.
工人永远都不会缺
There are always more workers.
现在别烦我
Not now.
告诉你  德国佬
You know, Fritz.
总有一天  老子也会有根棍子
One of these days I'm going to have a stick of my own.
伙计们
Fellas.
你是谁？
Who are you suppose to be?
美国队长
Captain America.
你说啥？
I, beg your pardon?
怎么着  所有人都走吗？
What are we taking, everybody?
我来自夫勒斯诺  帅哥
I'm from Fresno, ace.
还有其他人吗？
There anybody else?
我在找詹姆斯・巴恩斯中士
I'm looking for a Sergeant James Barnes.
工厂里有个隔离病房
There's an isolation ward in the factory.
被带去那的人都没回来
No one's ever come back from it.
好吧
All right.
林木线在西北方  离大门八十码
The tree line is northwest, it's eighty yards past the gate.
你们出去  给他们点颜色看看
Get out fast, and give them hell.
我找到其他人后和你们会合
I'll meet you guys in the clearing with anybody else I find.
等等  你知道你在做什么吗？
Wait. You know what you're doing?
当然  我揍了阿道夫・希特勒两百多次了
Yeah. I knocked out Adolph Hitler over 200 times.
你知道怎么用吗？
You know how to use that thing?
好吧
Okay.
怎么回事？
What is happening?
这货可不是别克
Not exactly a Buick.
- 这是点火器  - 啥？
- That's Zündung. - Zündung?
快启动
Get going, Dum Dum.
我不知道你还会说德语
I didn't know you spoke German.
最近在勒阿弗尔学的
I recently mastered at Le Havre.
顺便  法国妞正点多了
Plus the French girls much cuter.
这还用说吗
That's the resume.
不  你在干什么？
No, no, what are you doing?
我们的士兵不是对手
Our forces are out matched.
继续走
Keep moving.
拿手榴弹
Grab a grenade.
鹿仔
Bucky.
我的天
Oh my God.
是我  史蒂夫
It's me, it's Steve.
史蒂夫
Steve.
- 来  - 史蒂夫
- Come on. - Steve.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我还以为你更矮？
I thought you were smaller?
快来
Come on.
你是怎么回事？
What happened to you?
我加入了军队
I joined the army.
痛吗？
Did it hurt?
有点
A little.
- 会一直痛吗？  - 目前为止还在痛
- Permanent? - So far.
美国队长
Captain America.
我真激动
How exciting.
我可是你的粉丝
I am a great fan of your films.
这么说厄斯金博士还是成功了
So Doctor Erskine managed it after all.
虽然没什么进步  但是
Not exactly an improvement, but, still.
还是很不错
Impressive.
你等着瞧吧
You've got no idea.
是吗
Haven't I.
不管厄斯金对你说了什么
No matter what lies Erskine told you.
我才是他最成功的成果
You see I was his greatest success.
你没有变成这鬼模样吧？
You don't have one of those, do you?
你被骗了  队长
You are deluded, Captain.
你假装自己是个普通士兵
You pretend to be a simple soldier.
但你却不敢承认现实
But in reality you are just afraid to admit,
我们都已经不是人类了
...that we have left humanity behind.
像我们这种人
Men like you.
应该对自己的力量感到自豪
They embrace it proudly.
无所畏惧
No fear.
那你为什么要跑？
Then how come you're running?
来  我们走
Come on, let's go.
先生  我们去楼顶吗？
Sir, we go to the roof?
那我怎么办？
What about me?
那飞机只能坐一个人？
Where will I sit?
别划花我的车  博士
Not a scratch, Doctor.
记住了
Not a scratch.
来  我们一个个过去
Let's go. One at a time.
这儿肯定有绳子
Gotta get a rope or something.
走吧  快离开这儿
Just go, get out of here.
我不会丢下你一个人走
No, not without you.
布兰德议员  很遗憾地告知您
Senator brandt, I regret to inform you,
史蒂文 G. 罗杰斯队长
Captain Stephen G. Rogers
在敌后第三区域失踪
went missing behind enemy lines,
侦察队搜索过后也没有结果
on the third area. Reconnaissance has proven unfruitful as a result,
我只能宣布罗杰斯队长
...I must declare Captain Rogers,
在行动中阵亡
...killed in action. Period.
最后一架侦察机回来了
The last surveillance flight is back.
没有生命迹象
No sign of activity.
去喝杯咖啡吧  下士
Go get a cup of coffee, corporal.
我们不能拿史塔克怎么样  他是富豪
We can't touch Stark, he's rich.
也是军队最大的武器赞助商
And he's the army's number one weapons contractor.
- 而你什么也不是  - 恕我直言  长官
- You are neither one. - With respect, sir.
我不后悔我的行为
I don't regret my actions.
我认为罗杰斯队长也不后悔
And I don't think Captain Rogers did, either.
你觉得我在意你的想法吗
What makes you think I give a damn about your opinions.
我给过你机会  卡特特工
I took a chance with you, Agent Carter.
而现在美国的黄金男孩死了
And now America's golden boy,
还有很多优秀的士兵
and a lot of other good men are dead.
就因为你喜欢人家
'Cause you had a crush.
不是
It wasn't that.
我是有信念
I had faith.
那等到这个部门被关闭的时候
Well I hope that's a big comfort to you,
希望你的信念能给你点安慰
...when they shut this division down.
他们回来了  真不敢相信
There they are, I can't believe it.
那边在搞什么飞机？
What the hell's going on out there?
他们有些人需要医治
Some of these men need medical attention.
医生  我受伤了
Medic, I got wounded.
我愿意接受处分
I'd like to surrender myself for disciplinary action.
没这必要
That won't be necessary.
是  长官
Yes, Sir.
信念哈？
Faith, huh?
你迟到了
You're late.
这玩意坏了
Couldn't call my ride.
为美国队长欢呼
Let's hear it for, Captain America.
我荣幸地在此
I am honored to present,
将这个英勇奖章
...this medal for valor.
颁给我的好朋友
To my personal friend.
美国队长
Captain America.
美国队长？
Captain America?
队长  该你出场了
Captain, that's your cue.
我还以为他更高点
I thought he'd be taller.
一个在波兰和波罗的海
This one here in Poland, and the Baltic.
第六个在…
and the sixth one was...
大概
about...
在这  离边境三四十英里
...here. 30, 40 miles west of the maginal line.
我只大概看了一眼
I just got a quick look.
没人能做到十全十美
Well nobody's perfect.
这些是我们已知的武器工厂
These are the weapon factories we know about.
据巴恩斯中士说
Sergeant Barnes said that
海德拉把所有装备都运到了另一个地方
Hydra shipped all the parts to another facility,
而在地图上没有
...that isn't on this map.
卡特特工在和军情六处协商
Agent Carter co-ordinate with MI6.
我要每个同盟国都去找海德拉总部
I want every allied eyeball looking for that main Hydra base.
那我们呢？
What about us?
我们去给约翰・施密特一个下马威
We are going to set a fire under Johann Schmidt's ass.
怎么样  罗杰斯？
What do say, Rogers?
你背出了地图  你觉得你能搞定海德拉吗？
It's your map. You think you can wipe Hydra off of it?
是的  长官
Yes, Sir.
我需要一支队伍
I'll need a team.
我们已经有了最出色的士兵
We're already putting together the best men.
恕我直言  长官
With all due respect, Sir.
我也有
So am I.
那我们直话直说吧
So let's get this straight.
我们好不容易逃出来  你又想让我们去吗？
We barely got out of there alive, and you want us to go back?
差不多
Pretty much.
貌似听起来很有趣
Sounds rather, fun actually.
我加入
I'm in.
我们也加入
We're in.
日啊我也去
Hell, I'll always play.
但你得为我做一件事
But you gotta do one thing for me.
什么事？
What's that?
请客喝酒
Open a tab.
这容易
Well that was easy.
再来一轮
Another round.
他们怎么喝得下这么多？
Where are they putting all this stuff?
看吧  告诉过你
See, told you.
他们都是笨蛋
They are all idiots.
那你呢？
What about you?
你准备跟随美国队长去赴汤蹈火吗？
You ready to follow Captain America into the jowls of death?
当然不
Hell, no.
那个和我一样从布鲁克林来的小个子
That little guy from Brooklyn. I was too.
打起架来从不放弃
Don't like to run away from a fight.
我得看着他
I'm following him.
你还穿紧身衣吗？
Hey, you keeping your outfit, right?
知道吗？
You know what?
巡演取消
我还真习惯了
It's kinda growing on me.
好哥们要记住  天下没有不散的宴席
And remember that the best of friends must part, must part
再见  再见了
Adieu, adieu...
- 队长  - 卡特特工
- Captain. - Agent Carter.
女士
Ma'am.
霍华德为你准备了些新装备
Howard has some equipment for you to try.
- 明早去看看  - 听起来不错
- Tomorrow morning. - Sounds good.
看来你的精英部队已经准备好了
I see your top squad is prepping for duty.
你不喜欢音乐吗？
You don't like music?
我喜欢
I do, actually.
没准等战争结束
I might even, when this is all over,
我还会去跳个舞
...go dancing.
那我们还等什么？
Then what are we waiting for?
合适的舞伴
The right partner.
记住明天  队长
Pay attention, Captain.
是的  女士
Yes, Ma'am.
我会来的
I'll be there.
我小透明了
I'm invisible.
这下换成我了
I'm turning into you.
感觉真不好受
It's a horrible dream.
别想太多
Don't take it so hard.
也许她还有个闺蜜
Maybe she's got a friend.
初始特征不同寻常
Initial signature is unusual.
初始阶段一直是中性
Alpha beta remain neutral.
难怪罗杰斯能承受住
No doubt Rogers picked up on that.
看上去倒是挺无害
Seems harmless enough.
不像有什么值得担心的样子
Hard to see what all the fuss is about.
把这记下来
Write that down.
打扰一下  我找史塔克先生
Excuse me. I'm looking for a Mr. Stark.
四百余俘虏被解救
他跟菲利普斯上校在里面
He's in with Colonel Phillips.
想等的话当然也欢迎
Oh, of course you're welcome to wait.
我
I uh,
在报上看到你的所作所为
Read about what you did.
那事儿…
Oh, that...yeah.
那件事…
Well that's, you know...
略尽绵力而已
Just doing what needed to be done.
说话还真谦虚
Sounded like more than that.
你差不多救了四百人
You saved nearly 400 men.
说真的  没什么大不了
Really, it's not a big deal.
对他们的老婆来说可不是
Tell that to their wives.
我觉得不是所有人都结婚了
Uh, I don't think they were all married.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
那个嘛…
Well, that...you know.
取决于你怎么定义…
Tha..That depends on the definition of...
而美国的女人
And the Women of America.
都欠你的情
They owe you their thanks.
而既然她们不在这儿
And um, seeing as they're not here.
队长！
Captain!
大家都在等你  没事要忙的话就快来
We're ready for you. If you're not otherwise occupied.
卡特特工  等等
Agent Carter, wait.
看来找个伴也没什么难
Looks like finding a partner wasn't that hard after all.
不是你想的那样
Hey, that's not what you thought it was.
我什么都没想  队长  完全没有
I don't think anything, Captain. Not one thing.
你一直想成为军人  如今得偿所愿
Always wanted to be a soldier, and now you are.
就跟其他人没什么两样
Just like all the rest.
那你跟史塔克又算什么？
Well what about you and Stark?
我怎么知道你们有没有…
How do I know you two haven't been...
去吃什么芝士火锅
...fondueing.
你还是一丁点儿都不懂女人
You still don't know a bloody thing about women.
芝士火锅只是奶酪和面包  哥们
Fondue's just cheese and bread, my friend.
真的吗？
Really?
我不知道…
I didn't think...
或许你该动动脑子  伙计
Or should you, pal.
有时候你自以为你摸透女人了
The moment you think you know what's going on in...
结果发现
a woman's head. Is the
根本就不是那么回事儿
moment your goose is well and truly cooked.
我嘛  更注重工作
Me, I concentrate on work.
就现在来说
Which at the moment, is about
就是保证你和你的人都不送命
making sure you and your men do not get killed.
材质是碳的聚合物
Carbon polymer.
应该可以承受德国军刺
Should withstand your average German bayonet.
但海德拉可不会用小刀对付你
Although, Hydra's not going to attack you with a pocket knife.
我听说你有些装备
I hear you're uh, kinda attached.
用起来很顺手
It's handier than you might think.
有几个选项供你选择
I took the liberty of coming up with some options.
这个很有趣
This one's fun.
里面装了继电器
She's being fitted with electrical relays.
- 能让你…  - 那这个呢？
- That will allow you to... - What about this one?
不不  那件还未完工
No, no that's just a prototype.
是什么材质？
What's it made of?
吸音金属
Vibranium.
比钢更强  重量则只有其三分之一
It's stronger than steel, and a third of the weight.
它可以使攻击无效化
It's completely vibration absorbent.
为何不作为全军配备？
How come it's not standard issue?
这种材料在地球上实为罕见
That's the rarest metal on Earth.
你手中这一件
What you're holding there.
是绝无仅有的孤品
That's all we got.
快好了吗  史塔克？
Are you quite finished, Mr. Stark?
我确信队长还有些未完的任务
I'm sure the Captain has some unfinished business.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
很好  能派上用场
Yes, I think it works.
对服装我还有些想法
I had some ideas about the uniform.
听你的  伙计
Whatever you want, pal.
你一直在失败！
You are failing!
我们征服这个星球的计划就要成功了
We are close to an offensive that will shake the planet.
现在却一推再推  就因为
And we are continually delayed because,
你搞不定一个带盾牌的白痴
...you cannot outwit a simpleton with a shield.
这不是我的专长
It's hardly my area of expertise.
我只会发明武器
I, I merely develop weapons.
我又不会用
I..I..I cannot fire them.
完成你的使命  博士
Finish your mission, Doctor.
别在那之前就被美国佬给搞死了
Before the American finishes his.
长官！
Sir!
我很抱歉  施密特长官
I'm sorry, Herr Schmidt.
我们全军覆灭了
We fought to the last man.
显然还没有全灭
Evidently not.
还记得在科尼岛我逼你玩旋风飞车吗？
Remember when I made you ride the Cyclone on Coney Island?
记得  我吐了
Yeah, and I threw up.
这不会是报复吧？
This isn't pay back, is it?
怎么会呢？
Why would I do that?
你是对的  佐拉博士在火车上
You were right, Doctor Zola is on the train.
海德拉的人让他打开节流阀
Hydra dispatcher gave him permission to open up the throttle.
不管他去哪  他们肯定很需要他
Wherever he's going, they must need him bad.
他们快得像要去投胎  我们要快行动
Let's get going because they're moving like the devil.
我们只有十秒钟空隙
We only got about a ten second window.
错过了那个间隙
You miss that, window.
就要被火车撞死了
We're bugs on a windshield.
小心脚下
Mind the gap.
准备上了  兄弟们
Gotta get moving, buds.
拖住他
Stop him.
继续攻击
Fire again.
我就要打败他了
I had him on the ropes.
我知道
I know you did.
趴下！
Get down!
继续攻击
Fire again.
快杀了他
Kill him, now.
鹿仔！
Bucky!
坚持住
Hang on.
抓住我的手
Grab my hand.
不！
No!
坐下
Sit down.
这是什么？
What is this?
牛排
Steak.
里面是什么？
What is in it?
牛肉
Cow.
博士  你知不知道
Doctor, do you realize,
…这么一块高级牛肉
...how difficult it is to get a hold,
…在这可是很难搞到？
...of a prime cut like that out here?
我不吃肉
I don't eat meat.
- 为什么不吃？  - 不合口味
- Why not? - It disagrees with me.
氰化物怎么样  也让你肚子不舒服吗？
How about Cyanide, does that give you the rumbly tummy too?
每次我们想活捉海德拉的特工
Every Hydra agent that we've tried to take alive,
…都在我们能阻止前服毒自尽了
...consumed a little pill before we can stop them.
可你没有
But not you.
所以聪明过人的我推论
So, here's my brilliant theory.
你不想死
You want to live.
你在威胁我  上校
You're trying to intimidate me, Colonel.
我给你带了晚餐
I brought you dinner.
由于他所提供的宝贵信息
Given the valuable information that he has provided,
以及作为他大力合作的交换条件
And in exchange for his full co-operation.
佐拉博士将被送返瑞士
Doctor Zola is being remanded to Switzerland.
今早我把消息发去了华盛顿
I sent that message to Washington this morning.
当然是被加密了
Of course it was encoded.
你们的人还没解开吧？
You guys haven't broken those codes, have you?
不然可就尴尬了
That would be awkward.
施密特不会相信的
Schmidt will know this is a lie.
不管怎样他都会杀了你  博士
He's going to kill you anyway, Doc.
你成了他的障碍
You're a liability.
你知道他最多的秘密
You know more about Schmidt than anyone.
而且…
And...
最后一个被你害死的人
And the last guy you cost us
是罗杰斯队长最好的朋友
was Captain Rogers closest friend.
所以我可不敢打包票你会有什么下场
So I wouldn't count on the very best of protection.
自保
It's you,
…还是保施密特
...or Schmidt.
你自己选吧
It's just the hand you've been dealt.
施密特坚信他是在追随众神的脚步
Schmidt believes he walks in the footsteps of the gods.
只有得到整个世界他才会满足
Only the world itself will satisfy him.
你也知道他疯了吧
You do realize that's nuts, don't you.
当然
Of course.
疯不疯狂已经不重要了
The sanity of the plan is of no consequence.
- 为什么？  - 因为他做得到
- And why is that? - Because he can do it.
他的目标是什么？
What's his target?
他的目标
His target,
是整个世界
is everywhere.
明天…
Tomorrow...
海德拉将会称霸世界
Hydra will stand master of the world.
在瓦尔基里女神的庇佑下赢得胜利
Born to victory on the wings of the Valkyrie.
敌人的武器对我们都不堪一击
Our enemies weapons will be powerless against us.
若是一架飞机被击落
If they shoot down one plane.
还有数百架飞机会予以猛烈回击
Hundreds more will rain fire upon them.
砍掉一个头
If they cut off one head.
还会长出两个新的
Two more shall take its place.
海德拉万岁
Heil Hydra.
海德拉万岁！
Heil Hydra!
Heil Hydra...Heil Hydra!
海德拉万岁！
Heil Hydra, Heil Hydra!
海德拉万岁
Heil Hydra.
厄斯金博士说过
Doctor Erskine said that,
…血清不光会影响肌肉
...the serum wouldn't just affect my muscles.
也会影响细胞
It would affect my cells.
产生一个再生和愈合的
Create a protective system,
…保护系统
...Of regeneration and healing.
也就是说…
Which means, um...
我不会醉
I can't get drunk.
你知道吗？
Did you know that?
你的新陈代谢速率是常人的四倍
Your metabolism burns four times faster than the average person.
博士觉得那可能是副作用之一
He thought it could be one of the side effects.
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
你看了报告吗？
Did you read the report?
看了
Yes.
那你该知道是我害死了他
Well, then you know that's not true.
你尽力了
You did everything you could.
你相信你朋友吗？
Did you believe in your friend?
你尊重他吗？
Did you respect him?
那就别再自责
Then stop blaming yourself.
这样才不会有损他的尊严
And that was the dignity of his choice.
他肯定认为值得为你赴汤蹈火
He damn well must have thought you were worth it.
我要杀了施密特
I'm going after Schmidt.
只要海德拉还没被赶尽杀绝
I'm not going to stop
我就不会停手
'til all of Hydra is dead, or captured.
你不是一个人
You won't be alone.
约翰・施密特该被扔进疯人院
Johann Schmidt belongs in a bug house.
他觉得自己是神
He thinks he's a god and he's
还要炸掉半个世界
willing to blow up half the world to prove it.
就从美国开始
Starting with the U.S.A.
施密特的力量超出我们的能力
Schmidt's working with powers beyond our capabilities.
他只要穿过大西洋
He gets across the Atlantic.
就能在一小时内抹平整个东海岸
He'll wipe out the entire eastern seaboard in an hour.
我们有多少时间？
How much time we got?
据那位新朋友的说法  不到24小时
According to my new best friend, in twenty four hours.
他现在人在哪？
Where is he now?
海德拉最后的基地
Hydra's last base is here.
在阿尔卑斯山脉
In the Alps.
地表下五百英尺
500 feet below the surface.
那我们该怎么做？
So what are we suppose to do?
又不能直接敲门进去
It's not like we can just knock on the front door.
怎么不能？
Why not?
我们就这么做
That's exactly what we're going to do.
自大也许不是美国人的独有特征
Arrogance may not be a uniquely American trait.
但不得不说你诠释的比别人都出色
But I must say you do it better than anyone.
然而即便是你
But, there are limits,
也有做不到的事  队长
to what even you can do, Captain.
还是厄斯金的说法不同？
Or did Erskine tell you otherwise?
他跟我说你疯了
He told me you were insane.
他嫉妒我天赋异禀
He resented my genius,
还想否认本就属于我的东西
and tried to deny me what was rightfully mine.
可他却给了你一切
But he gave you everything.
那么
So.
你有什么特别之处吗？
What made you so special?
没有
Nothing.
我就是个布鲁克林的小个子
I'm just a kid from Brooklyn.
我可以和你耗一整天
I can do this all day.
你当然可以  当然了
Oh of course you can, of course.
但可惜的是我有点忙
But unfortunately I am on a tight schedule.
我也是
So am I.
罗杰斯
Rogers.
你可能用得上
You might need this.
谢了
Thanks.
我们进去了  立即进攻！
We're in, assaulting now!
行动！
Move out!
砍掉一个头  还会长出两个…
Got off one head, two more...
那就把这两个也砍掉
Let's go find two more.
停火
Cease fire.
你迟到了
You're late.
你不是要去…
Weren't you about to...
哦对
Right.
目标  纽约
上来
Get in.
稳住
Keep it steady.
等等！
Wait!
去杀了他
Go get him.
我可不会吻你
I'm not kissing you.
芝加哥
纽约
你就是怎么也不放弃是吧？
You don't give up, do you?
没错
Nope.
你本可以拥有神的力量
You could have the power of the gods.
你以为自己胸前顶着面旗子
Yet you wear a flag on your
就是为国而战了吗
chest and think you fight a battle of nations.
我已经看见了未来  队长
I have seen the future, Captain.
- 未来可没有国旗  - 这不是我的未来
- There are no flags. - Not my future.
你都干了什么？
What have you done?
不！
No!
我是罗杰斯队长  收到吗？
Come in this is, Captain Rogers. Do you read me?
罗杰斯队长  你…
Captain Rogers, what is your...
史蒂夫  是你吗  你没事吗？
Steve is that you, are you all right?
没事  施密特死了
Great, Schmidt's dead.
飞机呢？
What about the plane?
这个比较难解释
That's a little bit tougher to explain.
告诉我坐标  我给你找个安全降落点
Give me your coordinates I'll find you a safe landing site.
可能没功夫顾及安全了
There's not going to be a safe landing.
我要尝试迫降
I'm going to try and force it down.
我让霍华德来听  他知道怎么做
I'll get Howard on the line, he'll know what to do.
没时间了
There's not enough time.
这架飞机太快  正往纽约飞
This thing's moving too fast and it's heading for New York.
我得让他落在海里
I gotta put her in the water.
拜托  别这么做
Please, don't do this.
时间来得及  我们可以想想办法
We have time, we can work it out.
我正在无人地带
Right now I'm in the middle of nowhere.
要是不立即行动  会有很多人丧命
If I wait any longer a lot of people are going to die.
佩姬
Peggy.
这是我的选择
This is my choice.
佩姬
Peggy.
我在
I'm here.
看来要改天和你跳舞了
I'm going to need a rain check on that dance.
好吧
All right.
下周六在鹳鸟俱乐部
A week next Saturday at the Stork Club.
没问题
You got it.
八点整
Eight o'clock, on the dot.
不准迟到
Don't you dare be late.
明白吗？
Understood?
我还是不会跳舞
You know I still don't know how to dance.
我会教你
I'll show you how.
你来就好
Just be there.
记得让乐队演奏柔缓的曲子
We'll have the band play something slow.
我可不想踩到你的…
I'd hate to step on your....
史蒂夫？
Steve?
史蒂夫
Steve.
欧洲胜利日
敬队长
To the Captain.
先生
Sir.
去下一个坐标点
Take us to the next grid point.
但这里没有残骸的痕迹
But there's no trace of wreckage.
能量信号也在这终止了
And the energy signal trace stops here.
继续找就是了
Just keep looking.
已退役
又一记投球  是高飞界外球
There's a pitch, it's a ball high outside.
那么与道奇队比分为四比四平手
So, the dodges tied four to four.
计分毫无悬念  他挥动球棒
At the count no doubt, one swing of his bat.
这位小伙子有能力再次让对方三振出局
This fella is capable of making it a brand new game again
本场在埃比茨棒球场进行的比赛太精彩了
Just an absolutely gorgeous day here at Ebbets field.
费城人队把局面控制在四比四平手
Phillies have managed to tie it up four to four.
而道奇队还有三人在场上
But the Dodgers have three men on.
投球  好球
Pitch, it's a strike.
他屈起身  投球  挥棒  一道弧线
He leans in, here's the pitch, swung on, it's a line drive.
越过了格里姆森
It gets past Grissom.
瑞佐得分了  雷瑟跑向三垒
Rizzo will score, Reiser heads to third.
杜罗歇在等着接替他
Durocher is going to wave him in.
他们正要交接  但保持着稳定
They look to relay but they hold steady.
彼得・雷瑟以一记投入公园的…
Pete Reiser with an inside the park...
早上好
Good Morning.
或者该说  下午好
Or should I say, afternoon.
天哪
Oh my god.
我在哪？
Where am I?
你在纽约的一间术后恢复室里
You're in a recovery room in New York city.
道奇队以八比四领先了  道奇队！
The Dodgers take the lead, it's eight to four Oh ho, dodgers!
真是一场精彩绝伦的比赛啊  大家
What a game we have here today, folks.
比赛确实不错
Fine game indeed.
我到底在哪？
Where am I really?
我不太明白你的意思
I'm afraid I don't understand.
这场比赛
The game.
是在1941年5月
It's for May, 1941.
我知道  因为我在现场
I know, 'cause I was there.
我再问你一次
Now I'm going to ask you again.
我到底在哪？
Where am I?
- 罗杰斯队长  - 你是谁？
- Captain Rogers - Who are you?
罗杰斯队长  等等
Captain Rogers, wait.
全体特工注意  紧急警报
All agents, code 13.
警报  全体特工注意  紧急警报
...13, all agents code 13.
别紧张  大兵
At ease, soldier.
听着  我为那场表演深感抱歉  但是
Look I'm sorry about that little show back there, but.
我们认为最好让你慢慢接受这些
We thought it best to break it to you slowly.
接受什么？
Break what?
你一直在沉睡  队长
You've been asleep, Cap.
睡了大概七十年
For almost seventy years.
你没事吧？
You gonna be okay?
没事
Yeah.
没事  只是…
Yeah, just...
我错过了个约会
I had a date.
美国队长会在复仇者联盟中回归
睡不着吗？
Trouble sleeping?
你是来说任务的吗  长官？
You're here with the mission, sir?
是的
I am.
想让我回归这个世界
Try to get me back to the world.
还要拯救这个世界
Try to save it.
你以为这世上就你一个超级英雄吗？
You think you're the only hero in the world?
先生们  准备行动
Gentlemen, you are up.
复仇者联盟
挺带感儿的
A little bit swing.